Diane M. Margo

Los Angeles, California

dianemargo8@gmail.com | (352) 978 - 6552 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/dianemargo/

Summary

IS, Security Specialist working in IT Grid Services Security and Compliance with a background in computer science and business management experience. Highly motivated and enthusiastic individual who can work efficiently in cross-functional teams. Committed to achieving the organization's goals and contributing to its growth and success.

Key strengths include developing and maintaining project management strategies using an agile methodology, directing the creation and fulfillment of projects by hosting meetings to address priorities and progress, recognizing, and evaluating technical and complex problems to provide input on future developments of compliance, and assisting the team with projects that produce deliverables and solve challenges so that it follows Cyber Security standards.

Education

CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, LOS ANGELES

Master in Business Administration – Management

August 2021 – August 2023

CALIFORNIA STATE POLYTECHNIC, POMONA

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

September 2016 – May 2020

Experience

Southern California Edison (SCE)

IS, Security Specialist

May 2022 – Present

- Identify and categorize BES (Bulk Electric System) and their associated Cyber Assets to apply cybersecurity requirements based on the potential impact of loss or compromise, ensuring appropriate protections against misoperation and instability and enroll them into SAP and SQL databases
- Performed quality assurance on all assets for security patches and new enrollments, deploying security patches
 and collecting logging evidence via Splunk on Linux and Windows to ensure compliance with company policies,
 NERC CIP, and Cyber Security Standards while verifying system configuration and security.
- Facilitated vulnerability management meetings to enable the team to submit, scan, and assign responsibilities for risk management projects, providing necessary documentation and evidence for auditing purposes.
- Lead to ensure alignment to protect and secure BES cyber system information through reorganization of the NERC SharePoint with the IGAM (Identity Governance and Access Management System) project to streamline processes and improve data accuracy in preparation for automation transition.

IS, Security Associate

June 2020 – May 2022

- Directed the patch management process by tracking, evaluating, and installing cybersecurity patches for applicable Cyber Assets, ensuring timely application or mitigation planning within 35 days of evaluation.
- Managed SharePoint by overseeing access controls, tracking Grid Services members' permissions, troubleshooting user issues, opening support tickets, and coordinating with vendors like Microsoft as needed.
- Collaborated in Change Management activities by verifying and providing evidence in collaboration with vendors, managing escalated system issues to resolve tickets, and ensuring compliance with NERC CIP requirements through effective communication and teamwork with internal business partners.
- Undertook vendor and WECC audits and annual internal audits to ensure compliance with all applicable standards.

Professional Trainee

May 2019 – June 2020

- Contributed to the development of applications for software inventory management, focusing on baseline tracking and patch management.
- Facilitated the submission of access orders through SAP BMC Remedy for IT role responsibilities, ensuring access to platforms like SharePoint and Remote Desktop while validating with each stakeholder.
- Executed vulnerability scans using Tenable on NERC CIP environments on a bimonthly, monthly, and quarterly basis, assessing servers in our grid control systems and conducting vulnerability risk assessments for both new and existing enrolled assets.

Others

Projects

SCE Refresh Project: PAN 22 OS Firewall Refresh

July 2022 - February 2023

- Defined security standards for the project and reviewed documents to ensure they followed CIP requirements as a compliance lead for the project.
- Verified the asset's enrollment in CyberArk and ID ASM, providing evidence of enrollment along with accurate classification and recommendations for asset configuration as needed.
- Implemented changes for the decommissioning and addition of assets in the baseline, while generating reports on security patches, baseline exceptions, and identifying gaps before task closure.
- Diagnosed and resolved configuration and technical issues for new hardware.

SCE Intern Project: Automated Baselines

August 2019

- Aggregated data from all the NERC CIP environments from Industrial Defender into one file.
- Collaborated with compliance subject matter experts to reconfigure the manual baselines, enabling the Python script to run efficiently and ensuring consistency across devices with matching software.
- Conducted quality control testing on my application by manually gathering sample evidence and comparing it to the results generated by my script.

Leadership

Presenter and Planner – SCE Digital Grid Services Wonder Woman

January 2023 – Present

- Host activities to allow the women in Grid Services to network and improve connections.
- Demonstrate strong communication skills by effectively presenting assignments and providing clear examples.

Lead and Planner – SCE IT Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion

October 2022 – Present

- Review metrics from the organization to help leaders with decision-making.
- Participate in conversations about ideal work environments and the importance of video presence.
- Organized a speaker series event with Optum to bring in external experts to share their knowledge.

Facilitator and Planner - SCE IT Women's Forum

February 2022 – March 2023

- Successfully informed the audience through presenting and engaging with polls on topics presented.
- Facilitated a panel discussion by conversing and proactively asking questions to the company's VPs on the session's topics, prepping all VPs and their chief of staff with the agenda and questions.
- Coordinated a club-wide branding competition to empower the IT Women's culture and support inclusivity.

Technical Skills

Computer Languages:

Java, Python, C++, C#, C, MIPS, Git, LUA, HTML, CSS, Dart, SQL.

Computer Tools:

 Tenable Vulnerability Scanner, BMC Remedy Ticketing System, Industrial Defender Automated Systems Manager (ID ASM), Microsoft SharePoint, SAP Database, Splunk Logging and Monitoring, CyberArk Password Vault, PowerShell, IGAM, Flutter Software Development Kit, Android Studios Development for Google OS, Unity Game Engine Development, GitHub Desktop Developers Platform for Shared Code.

Technical Expertise:

 Data Structures and Algorithms, Discrete Structures, Data Science, Computer Logic, C++ Programming, Computer Organization & Assembly Programming, Algorithms, Formal Languages and Automata, Programming Languages, Machine Learning, Mobile Development, Big Analysis and Cloud Computing, Software Engineering.